# Edward E Griebel Jr.

edgriebel@gmail.com • 585-705-1093 • https://www.edgriebel.com/ https://github.com/edgriebel • https://linkedin.com/in/edgriebel

**SUMMARY** 

Language-Agnostic Full Stack Developer with over 20 years of success creating software solutions. Wide breadth of experience in multiple industries, languages, tools, and third-party applications demonstrates success. Excitement about creating code to deliver high quality systems that support business growth.

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Catalant Technologies**

June 2019 – Present

Principal Software Engineer

Rochester, New York

- Determine performance issues impacting system scalability and work with technical owners for prioritization and resolution
- Create and build consensus on engineering best practices to improve developer productivity and long-term supportability
- Create new features for customers and tools to enhance developer productivity
- Mentor and guide junior developers in Catalant's development environment and general software engineering practices

Technologies: Python, Flask, JavaScript, MySQL, Bootstrap, Docker

# Rochester Institute of Technology

Adjunct Professor

August 2017 – Present

Rochester, New York

■ Lecturer for undergraduate couses in Java, DBMS/SQL, and Software Engineering in Industry

PaychexJune 2013 – June 2019Middleware ArchitectRochester, New York

- Created system to rebalance 20,000 databases among 200 pools in Azure cloud using algorithmic, statistical, and machine learning techniques with TensorFlow, Pandas, NumPy, Jupyter, and scikit-learn in a Python pipeline.
- Built IT inventory system that provides a single source of truth for virtualized and physical hosts, JVMs, CLRs, databases, and middleware infrastructure with a HTML5 webapp and REST front-end. Relationships were sourced from external systems including AppDynamics, Puppet/Facter, ServiceNow, and Oracle OEM with a custom export to ServiceNow's CMDB.
- Custom Chaos Monkey randomly kills LDAP and SiteMinder middleware processes, and Java microservices daily in production and non-production environments. The Chaos Monkey is monitored and controlled by a Spring Boot web application and Splunk dashboard.
- Implemented AppDynamics on over 20,000 JVMs to replace our custom built system that collected and monitored JVM metrics and send alerts via SNMP and SMTP.

Technologies: Java, JavaScript, JQuery-UI, Oracle PL/SQL, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Python, middleware, AppDynamics, Application Performance Monitoring, ClearCase, Ant, Git, JUnit, Vagrant

# Axeda (division of PTC)

June 2010 – June 2013

Senior Software Engineer, R&D

Rochester, New York

- Full stack Java/Oracle/ActiveMQ JMS developer for IoT system.
- Lead for Cognos Business Intelligence integration with IoT data. Integrated Groovy with Cognos to script report creation, execution, publishing, and administration.
- Internal consulting for new and existing solutions for professional services and product management teams.

Technologies: Java, JavaScript, JBoss, Oracle PL/SQL, Hudson/Jenkins, JUnit, Cognos, Business Intelligence, Maven, SVN

Paychex 2005 – 2010

Lead Developer

Rochester, New York

- Lead team converting two existing external Java/JSP/Oracle applications to Web 2.0 and creating new external application from existing internal-only functions. Leveraged Hudson for Continuous Integration and automated turnover to QA.
- Mentored new developers, delivered technical training, and provided answers to challenging technical

questions for development team.

Member of architecture team to research and set five-year strategy for web application strategy.

Technologies: Java, JavaScript, JSP, Struts, WebLogic, Oracle PL/SQL, Hudson/Jenkins, JUnit, ClearCase

# **Frontier Communications**

2001 - 2005

Senior Software Developer

Rochester, New York

Created Java applications to build DSL circuits and track commissions. Automated generation of Excel spreadsheets from Hyperion EssBase saving two FTEs weekly.

# Global Crossing (division of Level3)

1999 - 2001

Senior/Lead Developer

Rochester, New York

Lead multi-site teams to create Java and Perl CGI telecom applications.

JP Morgan Chase

1995 - 1999

Lead Developer

New York, New York

Created trading systems in C/C++ and tactical applications for equity derivatives and HFT trading desks.

# **BlackRock Financial Management**

1993 - 1995

Software Developer

New York, New York

Developed systems in C/C++ for MBS mortgage, Treasury, and Repo trading desks.

### **EDUCATION** Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, Georgia

M.S. in Computer Science

Expected December 2022

Concentrations in Computing Systems and Machine Learning

# **Bucknell University**

Lewisburg, Pennsylvania

B.S. in Computer Engineering

- Senior design project creating reference implementation of DHCP protocol for RFCs 1531 and 1534
- Concentrations in Digital Electronics and Geology

# **CERTIFICATIONS** AppDynamics Certified Implementations Professional

November 2016

"An individual who attains the AppDynamics Certified Implementation Professional certification has demonstrated that he or she possesses the minimum acceptable level of knowledge and skills required to deploy AppDynamics Controllers, Agents, EUM Servers and Analytics Servers. This individual also has experience using AppDynamics APIs to extend and customize the AppDynamics platform."

### **PRESENTATIONS**

# **Axeda Reporting – A Guide to Service Intelligence** (Trade Conference)

May 2013

Axeda Connection Conference, Axeda, Inc.

Live presentation for Axeda customers to review and demonstrate new features added to the Cognos big data reporting product.

# **AWARDS**

# Paychex Paragon Award for Resiliency, Paychex

January 2019

Every year, five projects are chosen across Paychex that demonstrate resiliency, exceptional delivery, operational efficiency, etc. Our project, "Adaptive Load Balancing", was chosen. It routes requests in F5 BigIP GTM and LTMs across servers and data centers based on server load, real-time statistics, and other measures. Adaptive Load Balancing has reduced outages and improved response times for services using it.

## **AppDynamics Scale Award**, AppDynamics

November 2015

Awarded by AppDynamics to the company that was able to quickly deploy the AppDynamics tool across the most complex environment. Our team deployed the AppDynamics tool to over 2,000 JBoss, WebLogic, and Windows IIS servers across production and non-production environments.

## **OTHER ACTIVITIES**

# Leader, Boy Scouts and Cub Scouts **FAA Certified Private Pilot**

2007 - Present

[CV written in ET<sub>F</sub>X, compiled on 2020-03-28]